Preliminary Guide to the Stanley Hauerwas Papers, 1962-2018 and undated RL.00519
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2008-0123 and Accession 2009-0094, 12 boxes
  Addition (2009-0094) (2 items; 0.1 lin. ft.; dated 2006 and no date) contains two DVDs with programs by Hauerwas: the inaugural Will D. Campbell lecture series on Faith and Social Justices (2006) and Why Religious Diversity is a Bad Idea, from the Chicago Sunday Evening Club.
  Arrangement note
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - A-Bellah (Box 1)
  - Benson-Cartwright (Box 2)
  - Catholics-Divinity School faculty (Box 3)
  - Dorrien-Freeman (Box 4)
  - Fueston-Hibbs (Box 5)
  - Holloway-Jones (Box 6)
  - Jones-McCarthy (Box 7)
  - McCabe-Novak (Box 8)
  - Oakes-Reiner (Box 9)
  - Reno-Stassen (Box 10)
  - Steele-Watts (Box 11)
  - Waters-Yoder and miscellaneous files (Box 12)
  - DVD: Why Religious Diversity is a Bad Idea, 2006 (Box 12)
  - DVD: Will D. Campbell Lecture Series: Faith and Social Justice (Box 12)
- Accession (2009-0272 and 2009-0273), 7 boxes
  Additions (2009-0272 and 2009-0273) (7200 items; 9.6 lin. ft.; dated 2001-2008) includes travel materials, research and writings, and coursework and student correspondence from 2002-2006. Also includes reactions and press from Hauerwas's Time Magazine award (2001) and a manuscript of his book Hannah's Child (summer 2008).
  This addition has not been processed. Folders are listed but have not been further arranged.
  - Travel, 2003-2005 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Religion, Philadelphia, November 2005 (Box 1)
    - Mere Christianity, Furman University, Greenville, SC, November 2005 (Box 1)
    - Sermon on Mount, Wheaton College IL, November 2005 (Box 1)
    - East Carolina University, Greenville, NC, October 2005 (Box 1)
    - Idea Adventure, Xian History, UNC, October 2005 (Box 1)
    - Brownson Memorial Presbyterian Church, Southern Pines, NC, October 2005 (Box 1)
    - Southwestern University, Georgetown, TX, September 2005 (Box 1)
    - Luther College Regina University, Saskatchewan, September 2005 (Box 1)
    - Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, September 2005 (Box 1)
    - Preemptive Peace, Manchester College, North Manchester, IN, June 2005 (Box 1)
    - Huron University College, London Ontario Canada, April 2005 (Box 1)
    - Oklahoma Health Center, Oklahoma City, April 2005 (Box 1)
    - Day at Dayton University, March 2005 (Box 1)
    - Seattle Pacific University, March 2005 (Box 1)
    - Grinnell College, Grinnell, IA, March 2005 (Box 1)
    - Justice Theater Forum, February 2005 (Box 1)
    - Villanova, February 2005 (Box 1)
    - Virginia Tech and State, Blacksburg, VA, February 2005 (Box 1)
    - Wesleyan University, Middleton, CT, February 2005 (Box 1)
    - Kirk Ridge Retreat, Bangor, PA, February 2005 (Box 1)
    - Georgetown University, April 2005 (Box 1)
    - Xianity and Literature, Cambridge, MA May 2005 (Box 1)
    - Society of Christian Ethics, Miami, FL, January 2005 (Box 1)
    - Yale Divinity School, November 2004 (Box 1)
    - Assumption College, MA, November 2004 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Religion, San Antonio,TX, November 2004 (Box 1)
    - UNC-Charlotte, November 2004 (Box 1)
    - Asbury United Methodist Church, Phoenix, AZ, November 2004 (Box 1)
    - Fairfield University, CT, October 2004 (Box 1)
    - Central Methodist College, Fayette, MO, October 2004 (Box 1)
    - St. John's Epicopal, Tallahassee, FL, October 2004 (Box 1)
    - Univeristy of Prince Edward Island, Canada, October 2004 (Box 1)
    - St. Paul Episcopal Church, Richmond, VA, September 2004 (Box 1)
    - West Virginia Univerisity, Morgantown, September 2004 (Box 1)
    - Simpson College, Indianola, IA, September 2004 (Box 1)
    - Industrial Areas Foundation, August 2004 (Box 1)
    - Broadway Homecoming, South Bend, IN, August/September 2004 (Box 1)
    - Ekklesia Annual, DePaul University, July 2004 (Box 1)
    - Notre Dame Mennonites, July 2004 (Box 1)
    - Quaker House, Guilford College, June 2004 (Box 1)
    - Cosmos Club, D.C. Institute for Psychological Sciences, May 2004 (Box 1)
    - St. Thomas, Fifth Ave. NYC, April 2004 (Box 1)
    - Navarro College, TX, April 2004 (Box 1)
    - St. Bonaventure, NY, March 2004 (Box 1)
    - Princeton Center for the Study of Religions, March 2004 (Box 1)
    - UNC-Charlotte, March 2004 (Box 1)
    - University of San Diego, February 2004 (Box 1)
    - St. Norbert College, De Pere, WI, February 2004 (Box 1)
    - Society of Christian Ethics, Chicago, IL, January 2004 (Box 1)
    - Chapel of the Cross, Chapel Hill, NC, January 2004 (Box 1)
    - UVA Politics Department, December 2003 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Religion, Atlanta, GA, November 2003 (Box 1)
    - Eastern Mennonite University, Harrisonburg, VA, November 2003 (Box 1)
    - Seattle Pacific University, November 2003 (Box 1)
    - Baylor University, Waco, TX, October 2003 (Box 1)
    - Mt. St. Mary's College, MD, October 2003 (Box 1)
    - Xianity and Allegiances, DePaul University, IL, October 2003 (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Cambridge, MA, October 2003 (Box 1)
    - Baptist Carson Newman College, TN, October 2003 (Box 1)
    - Canada Mennonite University, Winnipeg, September 2003 (Box 1)
    - St. Vincent's College, PA, September 2003 (Box 1)
    - Oberlin College, OH, September 2003 (Box 1)
    - Ekklesia meeting, Chicago, July/August 2003 (Box 1)
    - New Garden Friends, Greensboro, NC, June 2003 (Box 1)
    - UVA, June 2003 (Box 1)
    - South Indiana Conference, Bloomington, IN, (Called Off) (Box 1)
    - Colorado College 2003 (did not go) (Box 1)
    - Northfield, MN, 2003 (cancelled) (Box 1)
    - Moravian Theology Seminar, PA, March 2003 (Box 1)
    - Yoder/Elkhart, March 2002 (Box 1)
    - Austin Presbyterian Theology Seminar, February 2003 (Box 1)
    - Servant Leaders School, Washinton D.C., February 2003 (Box 1)
    - Elon College, February 2003 (Box 1)
    - College weekend, February 2003 (Box 1)
    - North Park University, Chicago, IL, February 2003 (Box 1)
    - Colgate University, NY, January 2003 (Box 1)
    - Chapel Hill Bible Church, January 2003 (Box 1)
    - Calvin College, MI, January 2003 (Box 1)
    - Society of Christian Ethics, Pittsburgh, PA, January 2003 (Box 1)
    - Missouri United Methodist Church Ministries, January 2003 (Box 1)
    - The Church of the Holy Family sermon, March 2008 (Box 1)
    - Marymount College, May 2003 (Box 1)
    - University Presyterian Church, Chapel Hill, NC, April 2003 (Box 1)
    - Duke alumni, April 2003 (Box 1)
    - Georgetown Conference, April 2003 (Box 1)
    - Oklahoma State, March/April 2003 (Box 1)
    - Asheville/UNC Trip, March 2003 (Box 1)
    - North Indiana Conference, March 2003 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous materials: Travel, 2006; Students; Courses; Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Fan letters, 1995-2005 (Box 2)
    - Students elsewhere, 2002-2005 (Box 2)
    - Now Ph. D. students, 2002-2005 (Box 2)
    - Yearby and Barber, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Kate Blanchard, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Charlie Collier, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Jacob L. Goodson, 2004 (Box 2)
    - David Lui, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Maxon Rachel, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Jeff McCurry, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Dan Morehead, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
    - Sheryl Overmyer, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
    - Alex Sider, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Tristin Hassell, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
    - Peter Dula, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
    - Sam Ewell, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Christian Theology (XIANTHE) Students, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Advisers?, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
    - Divinity students, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Ethics, classes, syllabi, etc., 1995-2005 (Box 2)
    - Present: A-F, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Present: M-Z, 2003-2005 (Box 2)
    - Past 2001-2005 (miscellaneous correspondence) (Box 2)
    - Current applicants Ph.D., 2004-2005 (Box 2)
    - Students future, A-L old, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
    - Future M-Z, old, 1995-2003 (Box 2)
    - Campbell Lecture, University of Mississippi, November 2006 (Box 2)
    - St. Margaret's, University of Manitoba, November 2006 (Box 2)
    - Finland, 2006 (Box 2)
    - Rome, education, November 2006 (Box 2)
    - Villanova, PA, October 2006 (Box 2)
    - Gettysburg, PA, October 2006 (Box 2)
    - Chicago, October 2006 (Box 2)
    - Belmont Abbey, October 2006 (Box 2)
    - Georgetown, KY, October 2006 (Box 2)
    - North Park, IL, September 2006 (Box 2)
    - St. Andrews, Scotland, August 2006 (Box 2)
    - Aberdeen Vanier, September 2007 (Box 2)
    - First Presbyterian, Fayetteville, NC, August 2006 (Box 2)
    - Ekklesia Project (EP) sermon, July 2006 (Box 2)
    - National Health Ministries Association, June 2006 (Box 2)
    - San Antonio Catholic Theology Society of America (CTSA), June 2006 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Rochester College, MI, May 2006 (Box 2)
    - Bonhoeffer's Friendship Poem, January 2006 (Box 2)
    - Bonhoeffer's Poetry, Oxford, UK, January 2006 (Box 2)
    - Ireland, etc., 2006 (Box 2)
    - Christianity and the Social Crisis, deadline June 1, 2006 (Box 2)
    - Idaho, March 2006 (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Virginia Theology Seminar, May 2006 (Box 2)
    - Enda's event in Ireland, April 2006 (Box 2)
    - University of Illionois, Thulin Lecture, April 2006 (Box 2)
    - Ferrum College, VA, April 2006 (Box 2)
    - Ohio University, Religion and Violence, March 2006 (Box 2)
    - Abilene Christian University, TX, March 2006 (Box 2)
    - University of Dayton, OH, March 2006 (Box 2)
    - Seattle University, March 2006 (Box 2)
    - St. Thomas Church, PA, February 2006 (Box 2)
    - Boston College, February 2006 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2005 (Box 2)
  - Writings, essays, papers, reviews (Box 3)
    - Review of Growing Old in Christ, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Radical Democracy, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Abolition of War, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Speak No Evil, Duke, 2005 (Box 3)
    - The End of Protestantism and the Methodist Contribution (Box 3)
    - Leaving Ruins, Kaye Festschrift (Box 3)
    - A Recall to Christian Teachings: Catholic Social Teachings, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Baylor, Heart of Texas, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Teen: Why Did Jesus Have to Die? (Box 3)
    - Fish and the University, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Berry essay (Box 3)
    - The Sacrifice of Man, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
    - Theological Knowledges and Knowledges of the University, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Witham Review: Ciffords, 2005 (Box 3)
    - Review of Grain of the Universe: The Church's Witness and Natural Theology, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Capital Punishment (Box 3)
    - Writings and sermons, 1985-2004 (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous writings and sermons (7 folders) (Box 3)
  - Student files (Box 4)
    - Jana's Wedding, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Jana Bennett, 2003-2004 (Box 4)
    - Kate Blanchard, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Jason Byassee, 2002-2003 (Box 4)
    - Richard Patrick Church, 1996-2003 (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Peter Dula, 1996-2005 (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Chris Franks, 1993-2003 (Box 4)
    - Johann Friedrich Gugelmann, 1999-2006 (Box 4)
    - Lee In-Yong, 2002-2006 (Box 4)
    - R.L. Owens, 2000-2004 (Box 4)
    - Jeff McCurry, 1998-2005 (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Alex Sider, 199-2005 (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box 5)
    - Articles on September 11, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Reflections and letters, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    - Lots more fame, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    - Interviews, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    - TIME fame, 2001 (Box 5)
    - TIME, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Reactions from people, 2003 (Box 5)
    - Sermon, September 11, 2002 (Box 5)
    - South Atlantic Quarterly, September 11, 2001 issue (Box 5)
    - Loose material, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - Loose correspondence (Box 6)
  - Hannah's Child manuscript, Summer 2008 (Box 7)
    - Chapter 1: On Being Saved (Box 7)
    - Chapter 2: Work and Family (Box 7)
    - Chapter 3: Yale (Box 7)
    - Chapter 4: The Sixties, Augustana, Teaching (Box 7)
    - Chapter 5: Notre Dame: The Good Years (Box 7)
    - Chapter 6: Notre Dame: The Bad Years (Box 7)
    - Chapter 7: Notre Dame: The Final Years (Box 7)
    - Chapter 8: Duke: The Early Years (Box 7)
    - Chapter 9: Paula (Box 7)
    - Chapter 10: Friends, Institutions, Students (Box 7)
    - Chapter 11: Ordinary Time (Box 7)
    - Chapter 12: Last Things (Box 7)
- Accession (2012-0039), dated 2005-2011, 2 boxes
  Speaking/travel files, student files, correspondence, and writings. Arranged alphabetically within sub-series.
  - Student files, A-Z, 22 folders (Box 1)
  - Writings (Box 1)
    - Abolishing War? An Appeal to Christian Leaders and Theologians (Box 1)
    - Abnormality of War (Box 1)
    - Banhoeffin Panel (Box 1)
    - Church of the Holy Family Sermon (Box 1)
    - Companion to Summa Theologiae, 2006 (Box 1)
    - C.S. Lewis and Violence (Box 1)
    - Duke University: The Good of this Place (Box 1)
    - Father's Funeral Sermon (Box 1)
    - Franklin seminar (Box 1)
    - Goodson Chapel Sermon (Box 1)
    - Love's Work: Discerning the Body Sermon (Box 1)
    - Marriage of Sheryl Overmeyer and Andy Grubb (Box 1)
    - MLK and Christian Nonviolence Sermon (Box 1)
    - Modern Theology (Box 1)
    - Preliminary Thoughts on Goodness Sermon (Box 1)
    - Open Letter (Box 1)
    - Response: Jeff Stout's Democracy and Tradition (Box 1)
    - Response to John Bowlin: What is Radical about the Ordinary? (Box 1)
    - Scriptural Reasoning Group (Box 1)
    - War and the American Dream (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2009-2011, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Travel and Speech Files (Box 2)
    - AAR, Chicago, 2008 (Box 2)
    - AAR, Atlanta, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Aarhus University, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Amnesty lecture, Oxford, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Ann Loades, 2007 (Box 2)
    - APSA, Toronto, 2009 (Box 2)
    - AZUSA Pacific, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Baylor University, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Belmont University, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Bishop's Lecture, Birmingham College, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Carey Theological College, Vancouver, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Carl Lecture, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Catholic University, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Centenary College of Louisiana, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Center for Spirituality, Theology, and Health, Duke University, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Charlotte, NC - Myers Park, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Christian Labor Association of Canada, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Church of the Holy Family, 2011 (Box 2)
    - Church of the Incarnation, Dallas, 2010 (Box 2)
    - College of Holy Cross, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Corcordia Seminary, St. Louis, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Denver, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Duke Roundtable, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Eastern Mennonite Seminary, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Eckerd College, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Ekklesia Project, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Ekklesia Project, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Ekklesia Project, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Ekklesia Project, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Fondazione per la Sussidiareta, Milan, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Georgetown University, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Goodwin Conference, Duke University, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Granada, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Grandeur of Reason, Rome, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Greenbelt Festival, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Hauerwas Gathering, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Holmer Lecture, University of Minnesota, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Houghton College, New York, 2009 (Box 2)
    - IAF, Phoenix, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Indiana Wesleyan University, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Institut Catholique de Paris, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Jonas' Baptism, St. Bartholomew's Church, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Journey Group visiting Duke, 2010 (Box 2)
    - King's College, New York, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Knoxville, 2008 (Box 2)
    - MacIntyre Conference, 2008 (Box 2)
    - MacIntyre Honorary Degree, Duke University, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Metanexus, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Milan, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Mt. Union College, 2010 (Box 2)
    - NACUC, Duke, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Nazarene Theological Seminary: Conversation with Lindbeck and Burrell, 2007 (Box 2)
    - New York Encounter, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Pastor-Theologian Program, Quebec, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Peace Among Peoples Conference, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Prayer of Resistance, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Princeton: Youth, Church, Culture, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Religion and Modernity, Michigan State, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Rimini, Italy, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Rimini, Italy, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Rocky Mountain College, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Sabbatical, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Samford University, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Society of Biblical Literature, Atlanta, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Society of Christian Ethics, Chicago, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Society of Christian Ethics, San Jose, 2010 (Box 2)
    - St. Anne's Portsmouth Center, Bistol, Virginia, 2009 (Box 2)
    - St. James, Marietta, Georgia, 2010 (Box 2)
    - St. Luke's, Atlanta, Georgia, 2010 (Box 2)
    - St. Mark's, Niagara on the Lake, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Tennessee Wesleyan College, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Tocher Lecture, Topeka, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Toronto, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Union Theological Seminary, 2006 (Box 2)
    - University of Notre Dame, 2009 (Box 2)
    - University of Sheffield, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Valparaiso, Kentucky, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Vanier visit, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Virginia Conference Assembly, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Westcott House, Cambridge, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Wesley Theological Seminary, 2008 (Box 2)
- Accession (2012-0108), 1990-2001, 2 boxes
  This accession includes Hauerwas's writing files, dated circa 1990 to 2001. Along with drafts of essays and speeches, it also includes some editorial correspondence and notes. Content has been arranged alphabetically by title.
  - A-J (Box 1)
  - K-Z (Box 2)
- Accession (2012-0195), 2 boxes
  Arranged alphabetically within subseries.
  - Travel and Speech files, 2002 (Box 1)
    - AAR, Toronto (Box 1)
    - Center for Theological Inquiry, Princeton (Box 1)
    - Concordia Seminary (Box 1)
    - Conrad Grebel University (Box 1)
    - Davidson College (Box 1)
    - Duke Youth Academy (Box 1)
    - East Carolina University (Box 1)
    - Eastern College (Box 1)
    - Ekklesia, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Elon (Box 1)
    - Evangelical Theological Society, Toronto (Box 1)
    - First Presbyrterian, Bennettsville, S.C. (Box 1)
    - Governor's School, Meredith College (Box 1)
    - Hope College (Box 1)
    - Interfaith Ministries, Houston (Box 1)
    - King's College (Box 1)
    - Lafayette College (Box 1)
    - Lutheran Theological Southern Seminary (Box 1)
    - Mennonite Health Assembly, Knoxville (Box 1)
    - Pastoral Care Committee, Rock Hill (Box 1)
    - Peace Rally, Raleigh (Box 1)
    - SBL, Toronto (Box 1)
    - SCE, Vancouver (Box 1)
    - Second Baptist Church, Lubbock (Box 1)
    - Society of Catholic Liturgy, Mundelein (Box 1)
    - Southwestern College (Box 2)
    - St. Anthony Park United Church of Christ, St. Paul (Box 2)
    - St. John's Episcopal Church, Tallahassee (Box 2)
    - St. Peter's Catholic Church, Charlotte (Box 2)
    - University of Dayton (Box 2)
    - University of Nottingham (Box 2)
    - United Reformed Church Eastern Synod, Cambridge (Box 2)
    - Utah Valley State College (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Various Duke faculty, 1995-2000 (Box 2)
    - Michael Gallagher (Box 2)
    - Radical Transitions (Box 2)
    - SCM Press and other publishers (Box 2)
- Accession (2019-0074)
  - Lectures and Travel, 1981-2018; 2.5 boxes (Box 1-3)
  - Reviews, 2004-2017; 28 folders (Box 3)
  - Biographical Information, 1991-2003; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2018; 32 folders (Box 4)
  - Research, 2000-2018; 9 folders (Box 4)
  - Contracts, 2013-2017; 3 folders (Box 5)